apnic.net 2017-05-21

# APNIC Privacy Statement – APNIC

  * 1\. Introduction
  * 2\. How your personal information is collected and used
    * 2.1. Data used to support resource requests
    * 2.2. Data used for account and billing purposes
    * 2.3. Data used for conferences, meetings, training, and communication activities
    * 2.4. Data used for APNIC measurements and Ad serving
    * 2.5. Data used for recruitment
    * 2.6. Disclosure required by law or by enforcement bodies
  * 3\. Protecting your information
  * 4\. Data sharing and transfer
  * 5\. Accessing and changing your information
  * 6\. Complaints
  * 7\. Changes to this privacy statement
  * 8\. Questions or suggestions

## 1\. Introduction

The APNIC Secretariat respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the personal information that you provide. This privacy statement describes how the APNIC Secretariat collects, uses, and protects your personal information.

Personal information means information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable:

  * whether the information or opinion is true or not; and
  * whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form or not.

As the Regional Internet Registry (RIR) in the Asia Pacific region, APNIC distributes “Internet resources” comprising Internet protocol (IP) addresses such as IPv4 and IPv6 addresses and Autonomous System Numbers (ASNs). In so doing, the APNIC Secretariat collects personal information that is necessary to support its role as the RIR for the Asia Pacific region.

APNIC works to ensure that all information it holds is accurate, complete, and up-to-date.

Top

## 2\. How your personal information is collected and used

APNIC collects personal information for the following main purposes:

  * To support Internet resource requests
  * For account and billing purposes
  * To administer conferences, meetings, training events, and other communication activities (such as mailing lists)
  * To monitor network performance
  * For recruitment

Each of these purposes is described below.

Top

### 2.1. Data used to support resource requests

Internet addresses are public resources. To ensure that these resources are managed responsibly, the APNIC Secretariat must collect a range of information including:

  * Documentation of network infrastructure, plans, and customer details, which demonstrate the need for addresses requested; and
  * Personal information and proof of identity for people authorized by an organization to request resources and maintain database entries.

The APNIC Secretariat collects such information via web forms, on either the main APNIC web site or the MyAPNIC web site; from general correspondence by phone, email, post, and fax; and from face-to-face meetings.

The APNIC Secretariat uses this information to evaluate resource requests and administer accounts. It also may store some or all of this information for archival purposes, for the purposes of validating or auditing resource allocations in future.

Some of the personal information you provide may be publicly registered in the APNIC Whois Database. This is limited to contact details relating to the allocation of specific public Internet resources.

Please note that in relation to these network contact details, the APNIC Whois Database allows organizations to register “role objects” in place of personal details.

Also, APNIC policies allow for resource holders to choose whether their assignment details should be publicly visible.

Top

### 2.2. Data used for account and billing purposes

The APNIC Secretariat collects organizational and personal information, including banking details, for billing and account administration purposes.

All APNIC Members are required to provide an email address that will be included on a mailing list for membership-related announcements. This does not need to be a personal email address.

The APNIC Secretariat does publish the names and URLs of APNIC Member organizations on the APNIC website, but does not publish personal details relating to those Members.

Top

### 2.3. Data used for conferences, meetings, training, and communication activities

In order to administer conferences, meetings, training sessions, and communication activities such as public discussion lists, it is necessary for the APNIC Secretariat to use registration forms and voluntary subscription procedures to collect information.

The information gathered by registration forms is used to help plan and conduct public conferences, meetings, and training sessions. The APNIC Secretariat archives registration details to help plan future events and develop services.

The information gathered by subscription procedures is used only in the mailing lists you specify and may be visible to other list members. The APNIC Secretariat provides simple online tools to allow you to manage your own subscription status on mailing lists.

We may collect non-personal information about your computer and your visits to APNIC websites such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and number of page views. We may use this information in the administration of this website, to improve the website’s usability, and for communication purposes. We may also use that information to recognize your computer when you visit our website, and to personalize our website for you.

Certain events such as APNIC Conferences require photography and videography and such media may be used in APNIC publications, on the APNIC website, or on social media platforms. APNIC takes all care to inform event attendees that photography and videography make take place.

Top

### 2.4. Data used for APNIC measurements and Ad serving

APNIC uses online advertisements to measure aspects of the Internet’s infrastructure and support for new technologies, such as the deployment of IPv6 or the support of DNSSEC. APNIC does not collect personal information in such advertisements placed by APNIC. For more information about APNIC’s practices for APNIC measurements and Ad serving, please see:

<http://labs.apnic.net/privacy.shtml>

Top

### 2.5. Data used for recruitment

If you provide personal information for the purposes of recruitment, the APNIC Secretariat will only use your information for that purpose, and your information will be stored securely. You can update your personal information, or gain access to it at a mutually convenient time, by sending a written request to [hr@apnic.net](mailto:hr@apnic.net).

Top

### 2.6. Disclosure required by law or by enforcement bodies

APNIC may also disclose personal information about you if such disclosure is:

  * Required or authorized by law, or by a court of tribunal order; or
  * Reasonably necessary for one or more enforcement activities conducted by, or on behalf of, an enforcement body; or
  * Specifically permitted under the circumstances described in the Privacy Act 1988.

Top

## 3\. Protecting your information

APNIC policies and agreements contain specific protections for the confidentiality and security of information collected by the APNIC Secretariat.

All APNIC staff members, contractors, and Executive Council members, are required to preserve the confidentiality of any confidential information received.

In addition, the APNIC Secretariat maintains a high level of physical security and protection for all its computer and network facilities, and in particular for those in which personal information may be stored. APNIC takes all reasonable measures to ensure the electronic security of its computer systems and networks, including the information stored in APNIC offices, data centre facilities, and by third-party application providers.

Top

## 4\. Data sharing and transfer

The APNIC Secretariat may need to share information with other Internet-related organizations such as ICANN and IANA. The information shared is limited to that which is required for the respective purpose and is subject to those other organizations providing equivalent levels of security and protection.

Only Internet operational and troubleshooting applications may be downloaded from the APNIC Whois Database. Only information that is normally publicly available is transferred in these downloads.

The APNIC Secretariat does not share personal information that is collected from event registration forms, except as necessary for the conduct of the event in question. The APNIC Secretariat may publish lists of conference attendee names and affiliations on a website, as part of its commitment to open and transparent policy development but only the name of the attendee and their organization is listed.

The APNIC Secretariat does not share any mailing list subscription details, although it may on occasion forward external messages to a particular mailing list if it is relevant and appropriate for that list. The APNIC Secretariat does, however, provide publicly searchable archives of all public mailing lists, as this is necessary for the open and transparent policy development process.

Top

## 5\. Accessing and changing your information

Individuals and organizations that maintain information in the APNIC Whois Database are able to modify their own registration details by using either email or web-based methods. To prevent unauthorized changes there are strict procedures to identify people and verify their right to request changes.

You may modify any information you have used in a web-based form at any time. You will need to create a password and APNIC will then send you a personalized URL, which allows you to modify that information. This data will generally be deleted from APNIC servers after two weeks.

If you have subscribed to any APNIC mailing lists, you are able to unsubscribe yourself at any time.

If you have concerns about the accuracy or appropriateness of any other personal information held by the APNIC Secretariat, please contact us. The APNIC Secretariat will seek to correct any problems as soon as possible.

Top

## 6\. Complaints

If you believe that APNIC has breached any Australian Privacy Principle, you may make a complaint to APNIC by emailing , or in writing to:

APNIC  
PO Box 3646  
South Brisbane, QLD 4101, Australia

APNIC will investigate all complaints it receives. Once APNIC has completed its investigation and made a decision or finding, APNIC will inform you of the outcome and explain how it came to such a decision or finding.

APNIC is committed to resolving complaints fairly and promptly.

Top

## 7\. Changes to this privacy statement

The APNIC Secretariat will amend this statement from time to time. If there are any substantial changes, they will be announced on the APNIC website. This document was last updated on 12 March 2014.

Top

## 8\. Questions or suggestions

If you have questions or concerns about the issues discussed, please contact us via the contact details listed in section 6.

Top
